

ALDO GERON

SENIOR DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

PROFILE

Civil Engineer with experience in projects as Oil & Gas sector, road infrastructure, hospitality, industrial and services, within the private and government segment. Focusing mainly on the optimization of time and cost to fulfill the agreed legal and contractual commitments. Leadership and management of large work groups, as well as interaction with multidisciplinary teams. Project management abroad for two years, and in different countries of South America. Ability to create new work teams, restructure and create areas or departments to improve processes, optimize them, and obtain indicators for the best use of all available corporate resources.

EDUCATION

National University of Mexico (Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México)-UNAM

08/2008 - 09/2011

Civil Engineer courses to obtain bachelor's degree.

Antioquia University (Universidad de Antioquia, Medellín, Colombia)

09/2011 - 08/2012

Academic exchange abroad, specially focused at systems of transport & project management.

National University of Mexico (Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México)-UNAM- CED.PROF 09582595

10/2012 - 07/2013

Postgraduate in project management program with PMP Methodology. 260 hours certified awarded by UNAM.

MBA INFRAESTRUCTURE COMPANIES- EOI-SPAIN

10/2012 - 07/2013

https://www.eoi.es/es/programas/programas-postgrado https://www.structuralia.com/formacion/executive-mbainternacional-en-empresas-del-sector-de-las-infraestructuras 650 Hours certified awarded by EOI.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEWORK MEXICO – **Senior Development Project Manager** 10/2018–Present

- Management of: Asset analysis, project planning, budget & cost process, design process, biding & assign contracts process, construction phase, and delivery for:
 - -9 buildings/assets, 803,859 Square feet, 15,473 desks or workspaces.
 - Previous numbers mean 31% of Wework´s total capacity in Mexico.
- Budget portfolio management around: \$ 56.27 MDD.
- 82% of total portfolio amount below benchmark (under budget).

SELINA INTERNATIONAL – Development Project Manager 06/2016–10/2018

- First development people team hired in Mexico.
- Project planning, budget & cost process, design process, biding & assign contracts process, construction phase, and delivery for:
 - -2 locations in Costa Rica (Manuel Antonio & Jaco), previous means 418 beds & 6,780 square meters.
- Budget portfolio management around: \$ 2.5 MDD.
- Both projects developed below benchmark.
- Project structure organize, I got made it from scratch.
- Investment negotiation with building asset landlords to invest more money at project finance cycle (18%).

CONTACT

DATE OF BIRTH: 09/05/1990

PHONE:

55-87-94-34-34

WEBSITE:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/aldogeron-2674bb51/

EMAIL: aldogeron@gmail.com

ADDRESS: Mexico City, Roma Norte.

Zip Code: 06700

FIBRA UNO/ PARKS- Site Construction Project lead

09/2012-06/2013

- Co-leading 50,000 square meters of construction.
- Taking management of correlation process for design, sourcing, & payments.
- Delivery of warehouses & offices spaces to important clients as Sumitomo & Victoria Secrets.
- Budget management of \$ 65 MDP (MXN currency).

ODEBRECHT ENGINEERING & CONSTRUCTION CONSTRUCTION MANAGER- SCHEDULER- CONTRACT ANALYSIS LEAD

06/2013-04/2016

- Co responsible of construction management for PEMEX offices (13,500 square meters) as part of investment pushing on national master oil & gas plan.
- Back up support for 80% of total contract assigned by PEMEX to Odebrecht about earth-moving activities.
- Leading relationship & communication process with client (PEMEX), and making synergy with other stakeholders on the project, most of them with biggest construction companies (ENI SAIPEM & FLUOR).
- Construction management of 2 compression station gas in PIPELINE RAMONES II-NORTE (project from USA to feed & supply needed energetic to Mexico).
- This project was part of 2017 National geographic program about "Mega Constructions" http://www.techint-ingenieria.com/es/news/la-construccion-del-gasoducto-los-ramones-ii-norte-en-national-geographic-channel
- When construction activities were completed, started world company crisis, at this scenario I was assigned to adjust scheduler tasks regarding real situation furthermore I gave support to legal area to ending contract with PEMEX, claiming amount around of \$ 100 MDD.

SKILLS



